RESUME

Email id: aliahamedjak@gmail.com, Skype ld: aliahamedjak@gmail.com Mobile Number: +91 9566650280

AHAMED ALI.J.A.K Electrical Engineer



Objective :

Looking forward for **Electrical Engineer in MEP and Oil & Gas Projects** with a reputed organization that gives me an opportunity where I can improve my abilities and which provides an environment to share my skills with others so that I will be a part to success in that organization.

Professional Synopsis:

 Total 8 Years of Experience as 5 Years in Electrical Site Engineer for MEP Building Construction Projects as well as 3 Years worked as an Electrical Engineer in Aluminium Smelter & Refinery(oil & Gas, Minning) Construction Projects Including Substations.

Educational Qualification:

- BE in Electrical & Electronics Engineering from Anna University, India During the Year 2008-2011
- Diploma in Electronics Communication Engineering from State Board of Technical Education, India During the year 2003-2006

Career Summary:

Total Work Experience: 8 Years (7 Years Gulf Experience & 1 Year Indian Experience)

Organization : Asura Construction

Period : From Aug 2016 to Till Now

Position : Electrical Engineer

Area Worked : Apartments

Project Details : MSHEIREB DOWNTOWN DOHA PROJECT (QATAR)

Organization : Carillion Qatar Building Company

Period : From Feb 2016 to July 2016

Position : Electrical Engineer

Area Worked : Mandarin Oriental Hotel

Project Details : **BORDER POST COMPLEX AT AL ASWAD(OMAN)**Organization : Modern Centre Electrical & Sanitary LLC, Oman

Period : From Aug 2014 to Dec 2015

Position : Electrical Engineer

Area Worked : Police Station, Customs and Immigration Complex

Project Details : (Saudi Arabia)

MA'ADEN ALUMINIUM SMELTER & REFINERY PROJECT

Organization : Nasser's Al Hajri Corporation, Saudi Arabia

Period : From Aug 2011 to May 2014

Position : Electrical Engineer

Area Worked : Green Anode Plant, Bath Treatment Plant, Liquid Pitch

Terminal

Gas Treatment Plant, Calcination Plant

Project Details : **Jumeirah Lake Towers (DUBAI)**

Organization : ETA M&E, Dubai

Period : From June 2006 to July 2008

Position : Electrical Engineer

Area Worked : C3 Tower (34 Storey office & Residential Complex)

Duties & Responsibilities :

Involved in the technical and Management supervision along with site execution and highly driven in various project.

- All Electrical Low and Medium voltage installation works, which were being carried out as per BOQ, Specification and Material Approval.
- Preparations of MS (method of statement) for various electrical works.
- Planning and Execution on the electrical side for MEP projects closely monitoring the construction & Fit out activities, attending weekly meeting at site with other engineers and contractor and maintained Weekly status reports.
- Installation of all electrical works were carried out as per approved shop drawings ensuring compliance with safety requirements and as per standards.
- Coordinate with Mechanical, Civil, Architect Engineers, Discuss technical aspects of electrical system with contractor towards successful completion of project.
- Installation of Electrical system (Internal + External), Addressable Fire Alarm system, Security system (CCTV and Access Control), PA(Public Address) System, Internal & External Decorative Light fixtures, Power receptacles, Cable routing, Panel Board and Building Management system, Audio Video system, UPS System, Lifts, ATS Panels, Computer Networks(Fiber Optic Cables), TV & Telephone network, Lightning Protection system, LV Switchgear (SMDB,MCC...).
- Maintain good record keeping of activities carried out and inspection reports, surveillance report.
- LV Switchgear substation, Installations of MCC, Transformers, local control panels, distribution board's, Power outlets, field junction boxes, lighting panels, lighting fixtures & lighting jb's (indoor and outdoor plant lights) and cable glanding, Termination into Panel Boards.
- Familiar with testing activities prior to pre commissioning.
- Torqueing of MCC busbars, transformer terminals & motor terminals.
- Install and test the earthing of panels, switchgears, transformers, substation and building.Installation of lighting arrestors for structure & building.
- Perform the earth resistance test for all earth pit & earth points.
- Perform Instruments Calibration Of Pressure Transmitters, Temperature Transmitters, Temperature Element (Thermocouples & RTD).
- Installation of instruments stanchions, supports, instruments such as gauge, transmitters, elements etc. And instrument tubing.
- Following higher management time schedule instruction and advice, reporting work filed condition problem & following activities of other departments in site.
- Coordinate with contractor for the fast progress work on site implementation of advance system and material available as per requirement and conduct weekly site inspection and prepare Monthly progress report.

• Conduct inspection for Quality control, reporting, finding and recommendations.

Testing:

- Perform MCC's insulation resistance test, bus bar contact resistance test (ductor test) & bus bar continuity test.
- Perform insulation resistance test & continuity testing of cables such as power (MV/LV),control & instrument cables and witness of MV cables hi-pot test.
- Perform illumination (lux) test in plant's & buildings and prepare the test reports.
- Perform measuring the earth resistance test of earth grid, individual earth rods & all type of panels.
- Perform transformers IR test, winding resistance test & polarity test.
- Preparation of all testing functional reports for the client approvals.
- Operating System: Well versed in Windows XP, Windows 7& 8
- Packages: Ms-project Ms-word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Outlook.
- Computer Software installation.
- AutoCAD

• English, Hindi, Tamil, Malayalam

Date of Birth : 19.08.1986
Father Name : Kaja Mohideen
Gender : Male
Nationality : Indian
Marital Status : Married
Passport No : N3521116

Address : 37, Selva kader Street, Melapalayam, Tirunelveli

Tamilnadu-627005. India.

Email id : aliahamedjak@gmail.com Skype id : aliahamedjak@gmail.com

Mobile No : +91-9566650280

Julian G.Marquez, Turnover Co-ordinator, Flour Arabia LTD,

Email:julian.marquez@flour.com

Mobile No: +966 559374328, Telephone No: +96133561706

Jamal Mydeen, Start-up & Commissioning, Maaden Aluminium Company,

Email:rahamathullaj@ma.maaden.com.sa

Mobile No: +966 583158329